# Vishnu Ram V

Job intention : Full-Stack Developer

Birthday: 19/02/2002 TEL: 8667215433

Location: Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India E-Mail: vishnu.v1902@gmail.com

Website: vishnuramv.github.io Github: vishnuramv

## **ABOUT ME**

Self-taught developer with a strong eye for innovative design and a keen understanding of techniques geared toward optimum user experience. I see myself as a collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities like finding solutions to challenges. I'm also an undergraduate **Computer Science** student currently in my 4<sup>th</sup> year.

# **EDUCATION**

Chennai Institute of Technology B.E Computer Science and Engineering Jul 2019 - 2023

CGPA: 8.76/10(as of 5th semester)

Velammal Vidyasharam High Secondary Jun 2017 - Apr 2019

12th std aggregate: 76.6%

Everwin Vidyasharam Secondary School Jun 2014 - Mar 2017

10th std CGPA: 10/10

#### **EXPERIENCES**

## 101 Deploy Software Developer Intern Feb 2022 - Jul 2022

Worked on cryptocurrency based web application.

- Contributed on a nutrition tracking mobile application using React Native.
- > Translated requirements into polished website.
- > Participate in the design team's design tasks, responsible for technical coordination and communication with other departments or customers.

#### Cosgrid Networks Front-end Developer Intern Aug 2021 - Oct 2021

- > Developed a front-end application for help desk application with Angularis..
- > Worked on VPN application with Technologies like Reactjs and Electronis.
- > Researched third party APIs and service for future integration.
- > Followed agile work flow for development process.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### # Way

github.com/vishnuramv/Way-backend

Blogging website that use Artificial Intelligence to assist you in writing the blog. **TECH Stack:** ReactJs, Spring Boot, PostgreSQL, GPT2, Transformers model, Flask

#### # Dr.Diagno

github.com/vishnuramv/Dr.Diagno

App that predict the disease you might have based on your symptoms.

TECH Stack: ReactJs, Django, PostgreSQL, SKlearn, CatBoostClassifier

#### # VoilaTales

API for social media application that is used to share audio files instead of text or images or videos.

TECH Stack: Django, PostgreSQL



#### SKILL SUMMARY

- > Web and mobile app development
- > Object oriented development
- Leadership and project management
- > Programming and problem solving

#### **ACHIEVMENTS**

- > Techgig Code Gladiator 2022 Codeathon Finalist
- > Hack-The-Space 2022 Finalist

## FRAMEWORKS AND LANGUAGES

ightarrow React Native ightarrow Django ightarrow Firebase ightarrow GIT

ightarrow Python ightarrow JavaScript ightarrow Java ightarrow C++ ightarrow Solidity

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Django for Everybody Specialization Coursera University of Michigan
- > AWS Fundamentals: Going Cloud-Native Coursera Amazon Web Services
- Deep Learning Specialization Coursera DeepLearning.Al
- > TensorFlow: Data and Deployment Specialization Coursera DeepLearning.Al
- Python for Everybody Specialization Coursera University of Michigan

#### **EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

SECRETARY HACKERZ-CIT Feb 2022 - Jul 2022

Planned and organized the national level technical symposium - **HACKERZ**(Name of the computer science department symposium). While organizing this event I developed my soft skills like **leadership**, **event planning and organizing**, **communication** skill and etc.

#### Management Head GDSC - CIT SEP 2021 - JUL 2022

Organized various events under Google Student Developer Club - CIT and managed different teams and event process. In this we conducted technical event like hackathons and webinars.

#### President Web Development Club - CIT DEC 2020 - AUG 2021

Started web development club in my college and taught ReactJs and other web frameworks for more than 50+ students(My Juniors). Also conducted hackathons and webinars.

#### **WEBINARS**

Mentored high school students on topics like Python, Web Development, AI, and Game development through event like Funjinia and Bridge Course conducted by my college.

#### **HOBBIES**

- Learn some new skill.
- Listening to podcast.
- > Cryptocurrencies.